FENGYI PALACE
A lot has been going on
in the palace today.
I heard you're suffering from a headache.
These pearls were nurtured
beneath the ice in the coldest regions.
They are the most nourishing.
I hope this string of pearls
can alleviate Your Highness's pain.
You may leave.
I appreciate your kind gesture.
But my pain is a chronic ailment.
The imperial physician said
that curing a chronic illness
requires patience.
The death of Prince Jing
is also a chronic illness for Luomei.
You need to give her some more time.
Your Highness,
since it's a chronic illness,
it should be eradicated.
Your Highness, you know
the military power of the Pingnan Army
is a reliance for the Yin family,
but for Luomei, it is a burden.
One day, she will remove
this burden for the sake
of her husband's family.
Your Highness, you have no son.
What will you do in the palace by then?
The royal family most dreads
the relatives by marriage taking power.
How can I believe that you
will treat the Yin family favorably
after you ascend to power?
My feelings for Luomei are obvious to all.
If you're willing to help me,
her heart will eventually belong to me.
If I do not strive for it now,
I'm afraid I will regret it
for the rest of my life.
It's said that dried Tianjing Grass
is more delicious when cooked.
Can we wait for it to dry?
With such weather,
it will become dry in three or four days.
Brother, it's my turn.
It's my turn.
Erniu, come down.
Let your sister play for a while.
No!
Erniu,
as a man, you should give in
to your sister.
No.
Erya,
come.
The wheat is fragrant.
Tianjing Grass fills the storehouse.
You have a dirty face.
Don't run.
- Run!
- Erya! Run!
Don't run.
You've got something on your face.
- What is it?
- Here.
You are laughing.
Come over.
Don't run.
- The ground is covered with mud.
- Stop!
Don't chase me.
When you were little,
you must have been very naughty.
I wasn't just very naughty.
I was good at fighting.
I once knocked out two teeth
of the fat boy who lived next door to us.
I was only eight at that time.
Why?
He scared my mother with a dead mouse.
Later, when my mother found out
that I had beaten him,
she chased me to beat me for a day.
It seems
that the only person
who could discipline you is your mother.
Actually, my mother
never really hit me hard.
She just put on a show to scare me.
I guess all mothers are the same.
That's not true.
Every time my mother
used the paddle on me,
she really meant it.
One time, she nearly crippled me.
You must have made
an unforgivable grave mistake.
I just skipped school.
When I was a child, I disliked studying.
Once, I drugged my teacher
at the school with a sedative,
knocking him unconscious for two days.
When my mother found out,
she gave me a severe punishment.
You deserved to be beaten.
You say you disliked studying.
But I found you are good
at calligraphy and painting.
My mother hoped that I could learn
more poetry and etiquette
and become more composed.
But I have always aspired to be a general.
So, I didn't have much time to sit down
and write or recite books.
After the great fire in Qingzhou,
I became a cripple.
All day long, I was either
in the wheelchair or on the bed.
At that time,
besides painting, I played Go.
I didn't expect
I fulfilled my mother's wish in the end.
If Her Majesty had known it,
she would feel very sorry.
What about you?
Given your temperament,
I doubt you could stay
in the fruit cake shop for long.
Of course, I couldn't.
But every day,
I just loved to sit there,
watching my mother making fruit cakes.
You were craving the fruit cakes, right?
Of course.
Whenever my mother made fruit cakes,
she always saved the ones
with the most filling for me.
Your mother treated you so well.
No wonder
you just want to get a live-in husband.
If the Qingzhou fire hadn't happened,
what would happen
if I met you?
Luomei, you are a general of Great Yan.
What you shoulder
is different from others.
You shouldn't continue to grieve
and be dejected
over someone who has passed away.
Don't worry, Aunt.
Tomorrow, I'll return to
the training ground to drill the troops,
and I will not be negligent.
Well…
You know I'm not talking
about military affairs,
but rather your marriage.
You just said you came here today
to pray and relax.
A Buddhist temple is a place
of peace and quiet,
and it's not suitable to discuss
such worldly matters here.
I'm tired.
Let's go to the side hall to have a rest.
Wan'an Hall?
I don't know when
this Wan'an Hall was built here.
Let's go take a look.
Luomei,
today's military report informed me
that you led only a dozen light cavalry
to launch a sneak attack
on the enemy's scout camp at night.
My heart sank
as if falling into an ice cave
and then burned
as if doused with fire oil.
I keep thinking of how you are
diligently engaged in your duties,
both day and night.
Luomei, learning that you would soon
return to the capital with your troops
filled me with joy.
However, yesterday, I heard
that my father was worried
about the unrest in Baiyue
and has already sent an urgent decree,
ordering you to divert
and pacify the disturbance.
This means it will be
several more months
before I can see you again.
General,
this Wan'an Hall was built
by His Highness for one person.
The deities enshrined inside are all
to ensure the safety of that one person.
Apart from His Highness,
there are no other worshippers.
HOPING TO ENSURE LUOMEI'S
SAFE AND UNOBSTRUCTED JOURNEY
Luomei,
going to battle for our country
is your heartfelt wish.
I cannot ride alongside you
nor guarantee
that there will be no wars or injuries.
I beseech the gods and Buddhas.
Yin Luomei cares for the people
and disregards her own safety.
I don't ask for much.
I spent the night copying scriptures
to accumulate blessings,
hoping to ensure Luomei's
safe and unobstructed journey
and peace in all matters.
Since your first battle,
the Crown Prince has been praying
for your safety,
and this practice has never ceased
over the years.
It seems I misjudged the Crown Prince,
mistaking his genuine concern
for a desire for military power.
I believe in His Highness'
genuine concern.
Now that you believe in it,
you should agree to this marriage.
I've told you
that in the imperial family,
there is no love, only favor.
But the Crown Prince truly
cares about you,
which makes it
a really good marriage for you.
His Highness is very nice.
I just haven't made up my mind.
If Prince Jing were still alive,
I would never force you.
But the imperial edict for
the arranged marriage has been issued.
You have to get married anyway.
If you cannot be with the one you love,
just find a man
who truly loves and protects you.
Giving the man around you a chance
means giving yourself a chance.
PRAYER FOR BLESSINGS
IN THE 20TH YEAR OF ZHAOMING
Let her be alone and think about it.
Thank you for your help, Your Highness.
Your Highness,
please remember your promise.
WAN'AN HALL
Your Highness,
when did you arrive?
I saw you were inside
and didn't want to disturb you.
So, I've been waiting here.
So, you have done so much for me,
Your Highness.
But I am unable
to give you the same in return.
Do you know
that my father wants to reclaim
the Yin family's military power
through your marriage?
If you are willing to marry me,
I will do my best to protect
the Yin family for you and your aunt.
But if I were to use your genuine feelings
to protect the Yin family,
that would be unfair to you.
Luomei, I…
It doesn't matter.
You don't have to agree now.
But I hope you can remember
that what I said to you forever counts.
WAN'AN HALL
May the gods and Buddhas witness
that I built this temple
with no selfish intentions.
But as a mortal,
I have ultimately given in to greed,
desiring to keep my beloved by my side.
If my wishes come true,
even if I were to fall
into eternal hell after death,
I would accept it with contentment.
General,
the Crown Prince sent these to you
to congratulate you
on returning to the capital.
The best place to watch it has shifted.
In this world, everything changes.
Clinging to childhood memories
will make you miss even better sights.
I've never forgotten your ambition.
Even if you become the Empress,
the military power will remain yours.
You'll still be General Yin,
and I'll never confine you to the harem.
The legend about the red foxes
in Lushan is true.
As long as I, Murong Xuanlie, am alive,
I won't let anything upset you.
Good boy. You're so well-behaved.
Tasty.
I'll give you more
since you are so obedient.
- Is it tasty?
- Tasty.
I'll give you more if you are obedient.
Okay. You'll get more later.
How much longer does he
have to take this medicine?
It's hard to tell.
Based on the current condition,
it'll be at least ten days.
Make him sober as soon as possible
as long as the medicine doesn't kill him.
Each day Prince Jing remains outside
is another day of danger for him.
Don't worry. I understand.
My Lord, it'll take ten more days
to cure Li Qing.
Mei,
Qingyan said Li Qing would be cured
in ten days.
Great!
I like the gloves you made for me
very much.
Look at this. Does it look like
the Dengguo in Qingzhou?
It's called Red Fruit in Laowozi Village.
The ones picked early in the morning
are the freshest.
You got up so early these days.
Did you not sleep well at night?
Rise with the sun. Rest at sunset.
I like the life here very much.
After avenging Qingzhou,
I want to continue such a life forever.
What about you?
How did you sleep recently?
Do we need to catch fireflies
for lighting?
No. I had no nightmares these days.
Really?
Mei Lin. Mei Lin.
Big Brother.
Liu.
Well, Mei,
when no one is around,
don't call me Big Brother.
I feel awkward.
Awkward?
- What should I call you then?
- Whatever. You can call me anything.
In all, just don't call me Big Brother.
Mu Rong
Jinghe.
Fine. Just call me by my name.
Murong Jinghe,
I'm off to work.
Are you going to dry Tianjing Grass?
I'll go with you.
I'm feeling much better now.
I can work a bit with you. Let's go.
Miss, Sir,
you don't need to go.
This basket is for Madam Wang.
Thank you, Wei.
Mei, what do you like to eat?
Me?
Mei?
It's the annual Spring Harvest Banquet
of Laowozi Village in a few days.
Each family will prepare a dish.
It'll be very lively.
Mei,
I'll cook whatever you like to eat.
Wei, I…
Mei loves dragon meat.
Dragon?
What is it like?
I've never seen a dragon.
Wei, my brother loves talking nonsense.
Don't listen to him.
I like all kinds of food.
Everything is fine.
Mei is picky about people.
If she doesn't like the man,
whatever he cooks, she won't like it.
What does Brother-in-law mean?
If she dislikes the man,
she won't like the food he makes.
But Mei told me she likes
all kinds of food just now.
Could it be that Mei also likes me?
I got it.
What did you get?
You understood it wrongly.
What's going on with Wei?
There's something wrong with him.
Stay away from him.
There's something wrong
with the way he looks at you.
What's wrong with it?
Where are you going?
I'm going to catch a dragon.
- It smells good.
- Yeah.
My husband never cooks.
This man looks nice.
I heard he can do needlework.
He is very handsome.
Is he married?
My sister-in-law isn't married yet.
- We can ask him later.
- Right.
Sir, please wait.
Erniu's mother says you…
I'm married.
- Married?
- Yes.
You heard it, didn't you?
Madam Wang said
his family suffered a calamity.
I'm afraid his wife was…
My wife is very fine,
and I'll only love her in my lifetime.
Thank you for the kitchen.
This is her favorite snake broth.
I need to send it to her while it's hot.
Well…
His… Is his wife also in the village?
Isn't he here just with his sister?
Sister?
Wei,
these are…
These are all betrothal gifts for you.
I want to marry you.
I can hunt and farm.
I won't let you starve.
Wei,
we are leaving soon.
Where will you be going?
- I'll go…
- Wherever you go, I'll follow you.
Anyway, I'm the only one left
in my family.
Mei Lin, you saved my life before.
I won't let you live a hard life.
Wei,
actually, it was my brother who saved you.
Don't worry. We'll become family
after we get married.
I'll treat my brother-in-law well.
- Actually, I'm married.
- I know.
Madam Wang told me about it.
- Your husband has died.
- He…
Who said I had died?
Brother-in-law?
Who is your brother-in-law?
I'm her husband.
You… Aren't you siblings?
We are not siblings.
We are childhood sweethearts.
During our journey, I made many mistakes
and made my wife angry.
That's why she didn't want
to mention our relationship
in front of others.
Mei,
it's been so long. You should be calm now.
It was my fault
for making Wei misunderstand.
I…
They are a couple.
Madam, it was all my fault.
It's okay.
Well, I have good taste, right?
Just give up.
Stop it. Don't cry.
A real man doesn't need to worry
about getting a wife.
Madam.
All couples quarrel.
By compromising with each other,
you'll stay together
for a lifetime, right?
I think your husband's attitude
is quite nice.
You can forgive him.
Yes.
Actually, I forgave him long ago.
That's good to hear.
Come on. Try it.
Didn't you go to catch a dragon?
Your eyes are so poor
that you caught a snake?
The Book of Strange Records mentions
that snakes, originally named Hui,
transform into dragons
after 1,000 years of cultivation.
So, a dragon is essentially a snake,
and dragon meat is snake meat.
Roasted snake meat is more delicious.
You previously hurt
your spleen and stomach.
Meat broth will help with digestion.
You can have roasted snake meat
some other time.
It was my first time cooking.
Let me try it first.
I'm not picky about food.
How is it? Doesn't it taste better
than the dragons in the sky?
It's tasty.
I owe you this.
When we were in the wilderness, I said
as long as we could make it alive,
I would treat you to dragon meat.
Actually, I said Meat Dragon.
The Meat Dragon was made by my mother.
- Meat Dragon?
- It's a type of cooked wheaten food,
a steamed bun with meat in it.
In Qingzhou, every family made
Meat Dragons for joyful occasions.
Haven't you tried it?
I seem to have seen it in a border city
I passed by.
They call them meat buns.
How about we make Meat Dragons
for the Spring Harvest Banquet?
I'll take a try then.
I think I can make them.
As long as they are cooked.
As a couple, we can't just eat for free.
We should at least prepare something.
Since you are a couple,
don't sleep on separate beds.
Madam.
Madam Wang.
We'll sleep separately.
It'll be more spacious.
How can you say that?
Couples have arguments,
but they make up quickly.
If you keep sleeping separately,
your feelings will fade.
Why are you smiling?
If you offend your wife again,
I can't help you anymore.
Yes. I'll be obedient.
I'll listen to you and my wife.
That's more like it.
Take care, Madam.
We need to listen to Madam Wang.
We've slept on the same bed anyway.
Are you asleep?
Rest at sunset.
She should be asleep.
You can't fall asleep?
If you can't fall asleep either,
I can talk with you.
I…
I have nothing to say.
Sleep then.
Actually, I'm also quite sleepy.
There is a mosquito.
It's dead. We can sleep now.
I hope such days
can last forever.
YANMING PALACE
We've searched for such a long time.
How could there be no traces?
Your Majesty, here is the tea I just made.
Please try it.
Sit.
Let me see.
Fortunately, the burn that day
did not leave a scar.
The burn ointment bestowed
by Your Majesty is very effective.
Thank you, Your Majesty.
Concubine Yan, you are afraid of me?
No.
Your Majesty, you are a benevolent ruler
and have been very nice to me.
I'm not afraid.
I don't remember
you were skilled in these things.
Is the tea I made not good?
I'll make another pot.
No.
You did it very well.
I'm just not used to it.
Thank you for your praise, Your Majesty.
There is a lot I need to learn.
Maybe I scared her that day.
Concubine Yan, take a look.
- I don't dare.
- I allow you to read it.
Look.
The Prince Heir?
My brother has become
the Prince Heir of Xiyan.
I thank Your Majesty
on behalf of my brother.
I know
my brother relied
on Your Majesty's support
to become the Prince Heir of Xiyan.
It's because your brother
has the capability.
I merely took pleasure in his success.
From now on, there will be
someone backing you up.
So, don't be afraid of me.
I'm never afraid of Your Majesty.
I don't need you to serve me here.
It's late at night.
Go back to Fanghua Palace and rest.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Don't you think
she is acting more and more properly
as a concubine of Great Yan?
Concubine Yan is smart.
She learned the rules very fast.
Today, I heard the Noble Consort
praising her for being sensible
and courteous.
I just don't want to see her
being so well-behaved.
Send a letter of congratulations
to the Prince Heir of Xiyan.
Sure enough,
he didn't disappoint me.
Yes, Your Majesty.
Your Highness,
you're the reincarnation
of the Sun Kunlun.
So, the Princess Heir
should be the reincarnation
of the Moon Kunlun.
The union of the Sun Kunlun
and Moon Kunlun
brings the harmony of Yin and Yang,
ensuring favorable weather.
It will surely bless Xiyan
with everlasting prosperity.
As long as the Sun Kunlun
and Moon Kunlun unite,
Your Majesty will surely enjoy
a prolonged life.
Heaven begins with one.
Earth completes with six.
Once one and six unite,
all origins become clear.
May this be the guiding principle
and ultimate source of life.
Please, heavenly deities,
guide us to find the Moon Kunlun now.
How is it?
Found her. Your Majesty, I've found her.
The sacred woman reincarnated
from the Moon Kunlun
is in Zhaojing of the Yan Dynasty.
The Princess Heir is from Great Yan?
Father,
the Sun Kunlun and Moon Kunlun
are the divine envoys
of the Xiyan heavenly deities.
Now that the sacred woman
is the Moon Kunlun,
she must be from Xiyan.
I suppose she is just temporarily
residing in the Yan Dynasty.
Your Highness, you have a point.
Send our men to search
for her immediately.
Make sure to find the sacred woman
and bring her back to Xiyan.
Father, I request to speak.
I've been in the Yan Dynasty
for several years,
and I'm quite familiar with Zhaojing.
If I am to search for the sacred woman,
success is assured.
You can't.
You are the Prince Heir.
Why should you go to the Yan Dynasty?
This is something confidential.
You can't tell it to anyone.
Father, coincidentally,
I've received
the letter of congratulations
sent by the Emperor of the Yan Dynasty.
He invites me to discuss border trade.
Isn't this a great opportunity
given by the heaven deities?
God bless Xiyan.
LETTER OF CONGRATULATIONS FROM GREAT YAN
Alright.
Since this is about your Princess Heir,
you'll find her in person.
Yes, Father.
Your Highness, you are wise.
How were you sure
His Majesty
would believe in the reincarnation
of the Sun and Moon divine envoys?
Who among those at the pinnacle of power
does not yearn for immortality?
But you don't believe in immortality,
Your Highness.
Immortality.
Immortality is good.
Immortality would eliminate the regret
of unfulfilled ambitions
and dispel the ignorance
of overreached attempts.
Even as the seas turn
and the earth changes,
deep emotions are not bound
by shallow fates.
How wonderful it would be!
Mei Lin, my Princess Heir,
wait for me to go back.